{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Dharma","incorrectAnswers":["Karma","Nirvana","Samsara"],"question":"From the Sanskrit word for 'duty', what word refers to the teachings of the Buddha?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"George Orwell","incorrectAnswers":["Aldous Huxley","TS Elliot","Charles Dickens"],"question":"Who wrote \"Animal Farm\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Zeus","incorrectAnswers":["Apollo","Thor","Poseidon"],"question":"Who is the god of weather and lightning in Greek mythology?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hypotenuse","incorrectAnswers":["Perpendicular","Sine","Adjacent"],"question":"What is the word that describes the side of a right angle triangle that is opposite the 90-degree angle?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Cannes","incorrectAnswers":["Venice","Nice","Geneva"],"question":"At which city's film festival is the Palme d'Or awarded?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Freetown","incorrectAnswers":["Accra","Labe","Banjul"],"question":"What is the capital of Sierra Leone?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Naomi Watts","incorrectAnswers":["Melissa Leo","Frances Conroy","Laura Linney"],"question":"Which actress has featured in films including King Kong and Twin Peaks?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Kia Ora ","incorrectAnswers":["Tropicana","Rubicon","Sunny Delight"],"question":"Which well known fruit juice drink brand is the Maori word for 'Good Health''?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Shakespeare","incorrectAnswers":["Arthur C. Clarke","Isaac Newton","Enid Blyton"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Taming of the Shrew'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J. K. Rowling","incorrectAnswers":["Christopher Tolkien","Philip Pullman","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Georges Simenon","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Dan Brown","John le Carré"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Les Nouvelles Enquêtes de Maigret'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Starland Vocal Band","incorrectAnswers":["New Radicals","Faith No More","Bobby McFerrin"],"question":"'Afternoon Delight' was a one hit wonder in 1976 by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Groove Is in the Heart","incorrectAnswers":["Turn the Beat Around","Two of Hearts","In a Big Country"],"question":"What song did Deee-Lite have a hit with in 1990?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Kringle","incorrectAnswers":["Tart","Napoleon","Eclair"],"question":"Which of these is a Northern European pastry usually shaped into a ring or knot?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Fine hair","incorrectAnswers":["Twins","Small thimbles","Bibs"],"question":"The pasta capellini has what meaning in Italian?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kyrgyzstan","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","Thailand","Cambodia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders People's Republic of China?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Marlon Brando","incorrectAnswers":["Humphrey Bogart","Harrison Ford","Robert Shaw"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Stanley Kowalski in A Streetcar Named Desire?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"White with a blue cross extending to the edges.","incorrectAnswers":["Red with five yellow stars in the top left.","White with a red and blue yin yang symbol in the center.","Three equal vertical bands of green white and green."],"question":"What does the flag of Finland look like?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bangladesh","incorrectAnswers":["Indonesia","South Africa","Peru"],"question":"Bengali is a language spoken in which of these countries?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Austronesian","incorrectAnswers":["Turkic","Koreanic","Austroasiatic"],"question":"The language 'Malaysian' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Crocus ","incorrectAnswers":["Poppy","Calanthea","Rhododendron"],"question":"From which flower does the expensive spice of Saffron come from?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Lyndon Johnson","incorrectAnswers":["Napoleon","Oliver Cromwell","Vlademir Lenin"],"question":"Who tried to create the 'Great Society'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Eros","incorrectAnswers":["Hermes","Dionysus","Themis"],"question":"Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman god Cupid?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1842","incorrectAnswers":["1997","1945","1891"],"question":"In What Year Did Great Britain Gain Control Of Hong Hong?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Honduras and Guatemala","incorrectAnswers":["Mexico and Costa Rica","Nicaragua and Panama","Colombia and Ecuador"],"question":"If you flew due south from Belize, which countries would you pass over on your way to El Salvador?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Green","incorrectAnswers":["Maroon","Yellow","Blue"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Nigeria?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jared Leto","incorrectAnswers":["Peter Cushing","Kenneth Branagh","Luke Evans"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including Fight Club and Suicide Squad?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Peru","incorrectAnswers":["Belgium","Japan","Cambodia"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Ceviche?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Peter I","incorrectAnswers":["Nicholas III","Ivan IV","Alexei VI"],"question":"Who is regarded as the most influential monarch of Russian Romanov Dynasty?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Friedrich Schiller","incorrectAnswers":["Sebastian Brant","Agatha Christie","Rainer Maria Rilke"],"question":"Which author wrote 'William Tell'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Vacuum","incorrectAnswers":["Dark Matter","Black Hole","White Hole"],"question":"What term appies to space devoid of matter? ","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Salopettes","incorrectAnswers":["Finifugal","Futz","Fudgel"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'high-waisted skiing pants with shoulder straps'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Isaac Asimov","incorrectAnswers":["Ursula K. Le Guin","Philip K. Dick","Stephen King"],"question":"Which author wrote 'I, Robot'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Martha Graham","incorrectAnswers":["Isadora Duncan","Anna Pavlova","Twyla Tharp"],"question":"Who said, \"Nothing is more revealing than movement\" and is considered the most important figure of modern dance?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Astrid Lindgren","incorrectAnswers":["Charles Perrault","Enid Blyton","Beatrix Potter"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Mio, My Son'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Devo","incorrectAnswers":["Switchfoot","Genesis","The Hollies"],"question":"Name The Band That Had Hits With \"Freedom Of Choice\" \"Beatiful World\" & \"Working In A Coalmine\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Gaborone","incorrectAnswers":["Amman","Rabat","Valletta"],"question":"What is the capital city of Botswana?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Belgium","incorrectAnswers":["Luxembourg","Kingdom of the Netherlands","France"],"question":"Brussels is the capital of which country","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kazakhstan","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","Thailand","Cambodia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders People's Republic of China?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Astrid Lindgren","incorrectAnswers":["Charles Perrault","Enid Blyton","Beatrix Potter"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Brothers Lionheart'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Maroon 5","incorrectAnswers":["Styx","Oasis","Nickelback"],"question":"Which band was lead by Adam Levine?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Chile","New Zealand","Guatemala"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of The Loire Valley?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Aramaic","incorrectAnswers":["Hebrew","Latin","Avestan"],"question":"What Native Language Would Jesus Christ Have Spoken?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Galileo","incorrectAnswers":["Einstein","Michaelangelo","Plato"],"question":"Who was forced by the inquisition to recant his belief in the Copernican Theory?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Kabuki","incorrectAnswers":["Origami","Butoh","Aikido"],"question":"What is the name of the traditional Japanese theatre where performers wear elaborate makeup and costumes?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The structure and diseases of teeth","incorrectAnswers":["Furniture","Whales","Hair and scalp"],"question":"What is Odontology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Twister","incorrectAnswers":["Spinster","Twirlster","Rollster"],"question":"What is the slang term commonly used for a tornado?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Pocahontas","incorrectAnswers":["Sacagawea","Crazy Horse","Sitting Bull"],"question":"In 1613, which Native American woman was kidnapped by the British?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Turkey","incorrectAnswers":["Russia","Spain","Denmark"],"question":"Where did the real St. Nicholas live?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Romeo and Juliet","incorrectAnswers":["The Great Gatsby","Eine Geschichte des Universums in 100 Sternen","Madame Bovary"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'Two households, both alike in dignity, in fair Verona, where we lay our scene, from ancient grudge break to new mutiny, where civil blood makes civil hands unclean.'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"At a full moon","incorrectAnswers":["At midnight","On Halloween","On Mondays"],"question":"When do Werewolves appear?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Jamiroquai","incorrectAnswers":["Stereolab","Simply Red","Massive Attack"],"question":"Which Band Were At The Number One Spot In 1998 With “Deeper Underground”?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Moviegoer","incorrectAnswers":["Blood Meridian","On the Road","Ulysses"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Binx Bolling'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Budweiser","incorrectAnswers":["Guinness","Stella Artois","Corona"],"question":"Which beer brand is associated with the marketing slogan 'King of Beers'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jane Austen","incorrectAnswers":["Charlotte Bronte","Emily Bronte","Louisa May Alcott"],"question":"Which author wrote the novel \"Northanger Abbey\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Ragamuffin","incorrectAnswers":["Dipthong","Gardyloo","Pauciloquent"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'a person, typically a child, in ragged dirty clothes'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Michael Fish ","incorrectAnswers":["Gordon Jones","Harry Mortimer","Brian Daniels"],"question":"Which BBC Weather Man Famously Denied Reports Of A Possible Hurricane In 1987?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A group of thieves feel the pressure from the police when they leave a clue at their latest heist.","incorrectAnswers":["A general accuses soldiers of cowardice and their commanding officer must defend them.","The stepdaughter of a sadistic army officer escapes into an eerie fantasy world.","An ex-prize fighter struggles to stand up to his corrupt union bosses."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Heat?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bee Gees","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Culture Club","Dire Straits"],"question":"Which band did Barry Gibb form with his brothers?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Khachapuri","incorrectAnswers":["Ropa Vieja","Nasi Lemak","Moussaka"],"question":"Which of these dishes would you most expect to find in Georgia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ruble","incorrectAnswers":["Euro","Dinar","Leck"],"question":"What is the Russian currency?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red with a black two headed eagle in the center.","incorrectAnswers":["Three equal vertical bands of green, yellow, and red.","Black and green triangles divided by a yellow cross.","Red with a white cross that extends to the edges."],"question":"What does the flag of Albania look like?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Anne Boleyn","incorrectAnswers":["Catherine Parr","Anne of Cleves","Catherine Howard"],"question":"Who was Henry VIII's second wife?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Norway","incorrectAnswers":["Chile","Canada","Japan"],"question":"Which Country Is The Worlds Leading Exporter Of Salmon?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Apple","incorrectAnswers":["Blackberry","Microsoft","Google"],"question":"Which computer company was set up by Steven Jobs and Stephen Wozniak?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1949","incorrectAnswers":["1941","1945","1960"],"question":"When was the detonation of first Soviet Atomic Bomb?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Gitega","incorrectAnswers":["Tallinn","Male","Bissau"],"question":"What is the capital city of Burundi?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Emma Stone","incorrectAnswers":["Isabelle Huppert","Ruth Negga","Natalie Portman"],"question":"Who won the 2016 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of Mia in La La Land?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Jupiter","incorrectAnswers":["Earth","Mars","Neptune"],"question":"Which of these planets has the most moons?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Es","incorrectAnswers":["El","En","Ei"],"question":"What is the chemical symbol for einsteinium?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Anastasia","incorrectAnswers":["Natasha","Ilyana","Ivanka"],"question":"What daughter of Czar Nicholas II was falsely rumoured to have escaped death in the Russian Revolution?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A Nightmare On Elm Street","incorrectAnswers":["Halloween","It","Scream"],"question":"In Which Series Of Films Did Robert Englund Star As Freddy Krueger?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Liechtenstein","incorrectAnswers":["Argentina","Suriname","Philippines"],"question":"Vaduz is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jamie Foxx","incorrectAnswers":["Hugo Weaving","Warwick Davis","Timothy Spall"],"question":"Which actor has acted in both Amazing Spider-Man 2 and Dreamgirls?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"After a prince is betrayed and enslaved, he regains his freedom and comes back for revenge.","incorrectAnswers":["A group of thieves feel the pressure from the police when they leave a clue at their latest heist.","A car salesman's inept crime falls apart due to his and his henchmen's bungling.","After his father goes missing, a professor finds himself in a search for the Holy Grail."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Ben-Hur?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Albert Einstein","incorrectAnswers":["Isaac Newton","Stephen Hawking","Galileo Galilei"],"question":"Which famous scientist was taught math by Hermann Minkowski in the 1890s?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"27","incorrectAnswers":["15","47","70"],"question":"How Old Was Playboy Founder Hugh Hefner When He Launched The First Edition Of 'Playboy''?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Soup pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Shaped pasta","Stuffed pasta","Ribbon pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is anelli?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Clint Eastwood","incorrectAnswers":["Matt Damon","Robert De Niro","Sean Connery"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including The Good, the Bad and the Ugly and Million Dollar Baby?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Paul McCartney","incorrectAnswers":["Janet Jackson","Jon Bon Jovi","Sting"],"question":"Who Sang With Michael Jackson On \"Say Say Say\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hearing","incorrectAnswers":["Bees","The spread of diseases","Rocks"],"question":"What is Audiology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Swiss Chard ","incorrectAnswers":["Spinach","Broccoli","Cabbage"],"question":"Which vegetable is also known as the spinach beet or seakale beet?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Frances Hodgson Burnett","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Louis Stevenson","Arthur Conan Doyle","Joseph Conrad"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Little Princess'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dr Seuss","incorrectAnswers":["J.K Rowling","Enid Blyton","Roald Dahl"],"question":"Who wrote the children's book 'How The Grinch Stole Christmas''","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"St. Valentine","incorrectAnswers":["St. Patrick","St. Michael","St. Francis"],"question":"Which saint is celebrated on February 14th?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Lordi","incorrectAnswers":["Nightwish","Poets of the Fall","Stratovarius"],"question":"Which Finnish hard rock band released the album 'The Arockalypse'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Jack","incorrectAnswers":["A Billy","A Drone","A Boar"],"question":"What would you call a male wombat?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Dane Geld","incorrectAnswers":["War Bond","Sax Bandeg","Guerre Levy"],"question":"What Was The 9th Century Tax Levied To Fight The Vikings?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Josephine de Beauharnais","incorrectAnswers":["Marie Louise of Austria","Maria Walewska","Marie Antoinette"],"question":"Who was Napoleon's first wife?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Supermarine","incorrectAnswers":["Boeing","British Aerospace","Rolls Royce"],"question":"Which Aircraft Manufactuer Produced The Spitfire? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Bantamweight","incorrectAnswers":["Heavyweight","Lightweight","Subweight"],"question":"Which weight division in boxing lies between flyweight and featherweight?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Russia","New Zealand","France"],"question":"In which country would you find the city of Rome?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Daisy","incorrectAnswers":["Rose","Tulip","Orchid"],"question":"What plant species, whose scientific name is Chrysanthemum maximum, includes the shasta variety?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mahdavism","incorrectAnswers":["Roman Catholicism","Eastern Orthodoxy","Protestantism"],"question":"Which of these is not a branch of Christianity?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sabrina the Teenage Witch","incorrectAnswers":["Lisa Simpson","Spongebob Squarepants","Buffy the Vampire Slayer"],"question":"Which TV character owned a talking cat called Salem?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"AC/DC","incorrectAnswers":["Pendulum","INXS","Savage Garden"],"question":"Which band includes 'Angus Young'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["Greece","Britain","The USA"],"question":"In which country was natural gas first used as a form of energy?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Daniel Craig","incorrectAnswers":["Sean Connery","George Lazenby","Pierce Brosnan"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in No Time To Die?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rihanna","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Nicki Minaj","Ricky Martin"],"question":"Which singer released the song 'Te Amo'?","difficulty":"medium"},